Bruce Jackson and Diane Christian collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 2: Sound Recordings
  - Sub-subseries 2: Recordings made in prisons
    - 379 / 1218 / River Songs / Ramsey 2, August 17, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR1033; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 5 in.
      - 4. Black Betty (Hammer Ring) - G.I., lead
      - 5. Roberta - Snuffy Kimble
      - 6. Black Betty - G.I., lead; Matt, solo
    - 380 / 1219 / River Songs / Ramsey 2, August 17, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR1034; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 5 in.
      Contents: river songs. Same performers as SR1033. Recorded at Ramsey State Farm, #2. Collector: Bruce Jackson.
      - 1. Yellow Gal - Matt Williams
      - 2. Rattler - group, Matt solo
      - 3. Wonder What's the Matter - G.I. solo, 2 v., then group echoes
      - 4. 21 Axes (fragment) - Matt Williams
      - 5. Pick a Bale of Cotton - Louis Houston and group
      - 6. Long John - Houston, group echoing
      - 7. Wo, Lordy - Matt and group
    - 381 / 1220 / River Songs / Ramsey 2, August 17, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR1035; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, two track, mono; 5 in.
      - Side 1
      - 1. Stewball - J.D. Smith, Louis Houston
        Group repeats parts
      - 2. Shorty George - Louis Houston, lead
      - 3. Get Along Gator - G.I., Matt Williams, and Houston switch lead
      - 4. Sampson - J.D. Smith, Williams
        Song with some group participation. One verse only.
      - Side 2
      - 1. Sampson - J.D. Smith, Williams
      - 2. Curacy - Snuffy Kimble
        Spanish song. The log gives Smith's name as the performer.
    - 382 / 382-5 / 1203 / River Songs and Toasts / Wynne, August 18, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0880; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      David Tippen, Ebbie Veasley, Marshall Phillips, and Theo Mitchell. Recorded at Wynne Farm.
      - Side 1
      - 1. Rattler (song) - Tippen
      - 2. Wine Head Gin [?] (toast) - Phillips
      - 3. Titanic (song) - Tippen
      - 4. Hannah (song) - Tippen; Phillips behind him
      - 5. Cocaine Nell (toast) - Phillips
      - 6. Dangerous Dan McGraw - Veasley
      - 7. Jesse Jaws - Phillips
      - 8. Flicted[?] Anm[?] Pete - Veasley
      - 9. Corner of 47th and South Park - Phillips
      - Side 2
      - 1. Toledo Slim - Veasley
      - 2. Treacherous [?] - Veasley
      - 3. Joe the Grinder - Phillips
      - 4. Hobo's Convention - Veasley
      - 5. Feeble Old Man - Phillips
    - 383 / 1204 / River Songs and Toasts / Wynne, August 18, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0881; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      - 1. Hannah - Tippen, lead
      - 2. Stewball - Veasley, lead
      - 3. Tampa - Veasley, lead
      - 4. Wasn't That a Mighty Number - Tippen, lead
      - 5. Long Hot Summer Days - Tippen, lead, then Veasley
      - 6. Captain Don't Feel Sorry for a Longtime Man - Phillips, lead; Mitchell [?]
      - 7. My Old Black Girl - Veasley, lead
      - 8. Little Girl in the Gambling[?] - Phillips
    - 384 / 1205 / River Songs and Toasts / Wynne, August 18, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0882; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, stereo; 7 in.
      - 1. Midnight Special - Tippen, lead
      - 2. Shorty George - Tippen, lead, and Veasley, lead
      - 3. Groshick [?] Blues - Phillips, solo
      - 4. No More Corn on the Brazos - Tippen, lead
      - 5. Godamighty - Mitchell and Veasley, lead
      - 6. John Henry - Veasley, lead
      - 7. Subject to a Fall - Veasley
      - 8. Dog Ass Pimps - Phillips
      - 9. W[?] - Phillips
      - 10. Pimp's Toast - Phillips
      - 11. Raise Em Up Higher - Godamighty [?] - Veasley and Phillips
      - 12. Pick a Bale of Cotton - Veasley, lead; Phillips, Tippen
    - 385 / 1221 / MacDonald / Ramsey 2, August 18, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR1036; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 5 in.
      Contents: professional crime. Recorded at Ramsey State Farm, #2.
    - 386 / 1206 / Spirituals and River / Ellis, August 19, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0883; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, stereo; 7 in.
      Contents: river songs. Maze, Johnson, Alec, Sherrod, others. Recorded at Ellis. A note on the tape box back indicates that noise heard on the recording is a blower.
      - 1. Alberta (Mack Maze, Joseph Johnson, W.D. Alexander, Arthur Sherrod, Lawrence Smith)
      - 2. The Man Jesus (by Sandell) - John Cooks, lead; Willie Sandell; A.D. Williams; Saul William; Bonny Richardson; Alexander, speaking
      - 3. Close to You
        From hymnal
      - 4. God Is Standing By - Sandell, lead
      - 5. Lord I Want to Be a Christian - Alec, lead
      - 6. I Told the Captain He Don't Worry Me - Mack Maze, solo
      - 7. Easy Rider What Makes You So Mean? - start
      - 8. Rabbit on the Run - Chinaman, accompanying himself on guitar
      - 9. Jody's Got My Gal and Gone - Sandell, lead; same group as on "Close to You"
    - 387 / 1207 / River Songs / Ellis / 2, August 19, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0884; 1 sound tape reel: analog, stereo; 7 in.
      Contents: river songs, preaching. Same performers as SR0883. Recorded at Ellis.
      - 1. Alec's sermon - Alec and others except Sherrod and Maze and Chinaman
      - 2. Should [?] River [?]
      - 3. My Baby Left Me [?] - Sherrod
      - 4. Richardson sermon - all except Sherrod, Cook, and Sandell
      - 5. Hammer Ring - Willie Sandell, second lead; Chinaman; A.D. Williams; Saul William; Lawrence Smith; W.D. Alexander; Benny Richardson - first lead, Mack Maze
      - 6. Drop Em Down - Chinaman, lead
      - 7. Stewball - Chinaman, lead; then Richardson, lead
      - 8. Julie - Alec, lead; Chinaman; Mack; Smith
      - 9. Roberta - Mack Maze; long time
    - 388 / 1208 / Levee camp song (Ellis) / River songs, toasts (Wynne) / 3, August 19-20, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0885; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, stereo; 7 in.
      Number 1 was recorded at Ellis. Numbers 2 through 8 were performed by the same group as on SR0880-SR0882, and recorded at Wynne.
      - 1. I Can [?] a Whaler - Chinaman, August 19, 1965
      - 2. Jolly King Won't You Ramble - David Tippen, Veasley, Mitchell, and Phillips, August 20, 1965
      - 3. I Got the Crane Wing - Tippen, lead
      - 4. Titanic - Veasley
      - 5. Titanic - 2nd ending - Phillips
      - 6. Limpty Lefty McCree - Phillips
      - 7. Strange, Strange Things - Phillips; same as 52.14
      - 8. Signifying Monkey - Veasley
      - 9. I Got a Record - Veasley, lead
    - 389 / 1223 / River Songs / Ellis / August 20, 1965, August 20, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR1037; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, two track, mono; 5 in.
      Crosscutting. Discrepancies between the number of songs listed on the tape box and those listed in the log. Trinity Bottoms. Work groups. Recorded at Ellis. Collector: Bruce Jackson.
      - 1. Hammer Ring - David Tippett; James Sanders; Robert Daniels; Henry Scott, lead
        Song about Evalina
      - 2. Hammer Ring - David Tippett; James Sanders; Robert Daniels; Henry Scott, lead
        Song about Elnora - variation
      - 3. Down the Line - Tippett, lead; crosscut
        Song interrupted by tree falling on microphone
      - 4. Down the Line - Tippett
        Song ending with tree crash
      - 5. It Takes a #1 Tampa - [not given]
      - 6. Yellow Gal (name on tape) - David Tippett, lead
        Names on log include Willie Deason, Henry Wilson, Tom Washington. Song also ending "timber!"
      - 7. Hammer Ring - Scott, lead
        Hiss in background is a brush introduced by Tippett; fire nearby; third man is Daniels
      - 8. So Soon This Evening? - Tippett, lead, then Scott; Daniels joins in
    - 390 / 1209 / River songs, Mexican band / Wynne, August 20, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0886; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, stereo; 7 in.
      The first song is credited to Joe Mitchell and all others were performed by a Mexican American group. Recorded at Wynne.
      - 1. Roberta (solo) / 39 / (in 10 1/2) / por una
      - 2. For a Married Woman (names inside)
      - 3. Close to the Sea
      - 4. The Pel[?] - polka instrumental
      - 5. The Arrow
      - 6. The Drunkard
      - 7. Danzón Juárez
      - 8. Malaguena
      - 9. Los Caminos (Highways)
    - 391 / 1210 / Gospel, blues / Wynne, August 20, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0887; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono and stereo; 7 in.
      Joe Mitchell, others. Recorded at Wynne.
      - 1. Let the Church Roll On (stereo) - Eugene Engsby (lead) and others (named on tape)
      - 2. Big Gun Blues (mono) - W.T. Alexander (prisoner #151524)
      - 3. Little Girl - W.T. Alexander (prisoner #151524)
      - 4. Blues with a Feelin' - W.T. Alexander (prisoner #151524)
        From Muddy Waters record
      - 5. I Want to Know - W.T. Alexander (prisoner #151524)
      - 6. Ticket Agent Blues - W.T. Alexander (prisoner #151524)
        From Melvin "Li'l Son" Jackson
      - 7. Boogie tune - W.T. Alexander (prisoner #151524)
      - 8. Good Things Have Come My Way - Lee Mitchell (prisoner #133544)
      - 9. I Left My Home - Lee Mitchell (prisoner #133544)
    - 392 / 1224 / Beto and River Dub., 1965-1968, AFC 2011/009: SR1038; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 5 in.
      Side 2 is a dub of the Retrieve group.
      - Side 1, August 20, 1965
      - George Beto - interview
        Huntsville, Texas. On TDC.
      - Side 2, January 28, 1965
        Work songs recorded by A. Langley on Bel[?] (Unit Chon).
      - 1. Let Your Hammer Ring
      - 2. Stewball
      - 3. Every Time I Get a Letter from My Baby
    - 393 / 1225 / Sounds / River Songs / Ellis, August 20-21, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR1039; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, one track, mono; 5 in.
      Contents: cutting up logs, chopping, dogs, river songs. The first two selections were recorded on August 20 and the rest recorded on August 21. Recorded at Ellis.
      - 1. Miscellaneous chopping noises, August 20, 1965
      - 2. Hounds barking, August 20, 1965
      - 3. This Old Hammer Killed John Henry - Maze, Chinaman, Alec, Smith, and [?], August 21, 1965
      - 4. Drop 'Em in the Timber - Maze, Chinaman, Alec, Smith, and [?], August 21, 1965
    - 394 / Rivers Songs / Cutting up logs / Ellis / 1226, August 21, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0399; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 71/2 ips, mono; 7 in.
      Chinaman, Alex, Mack, Smith. Recorded at Ellis. The log gives the date as August 12 (probably a typo). Collector: Bruce Jackson.
      - 1. Working on a live cork log - Chinaman, Alec, Mack, Smith (stop and starts)
        No text; logging
      - 2. Julie - Willie Goodell (lead), Alec, Mack, Smith
        No text
      - 3. Julie - Alec (lead), Willie Goodell, Alec, Mack, Smith (first was bad go)
      - 4. Drinkin' That Wine - Chinaman, lead, Alec, Mack, Smith
    - 395 / Rivers Songs / Cross-cutting / Ellis / 1227, August 21, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0400; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 5 in.
      Chinaman, Alexander, Mack, Smith. May be the same group as on SR0399. Recorded at Ellis. Collector: Bruce Jackson.
      - 1. Hammer Ring - Chinaman, lead
        Song with crosscutting
      - 2. Crooked Foot John - Chinaman, lead
        This and one other in book
      - 3. Yellow Gal - Chinaman, lead
    - 396 / Rivers Songs / Ellis / 1228 / 203-9, August 21, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0401; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 5 in.
      Some mismatches between the tape box information and the recording log. Chinaman, Maze, Smith, Alec. Recorded at Ellis. Collector: Bruce Jackson.
      - Tape box list
      - 1. The Grizzly Bear
      - 2. I Need Another Waitress
      - 3. Eastham Talking Blues
        One stanza
      - 4. Convict's Prayer - Alec
        Poem
      - 5. TB Bess - Chinaman
        Toast
      - Log list
      - 1. Grizzly Bear
      - 2. Conversation about Jack a Diamonds (Captain Powell)
        Conversation about [between?] Bruce, Mack, Chinaman, Guard, Alec
      - 3. Send Your Back - Chinaman
        Four-line poem
      - 4. Convict's Prayer - Alexander
        Parody on psalm, "Lord is My Shepherd"
      - 5. T.B. Bess - Chinaman
        Soliloquy in couplets
    - 397 / Rivers Songs / Cross cutting / Ellis / 1229 / 203-9, August 21, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0402; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 5 in.
      Chinaman, Mack Maze, Smith, Alec (Alexander). Noted on the tape box: A.D. Williams 163504 waterboy. The number is probably his prisoner number. Recorded at Ellis. Collector: Bruce Jackson.
      - 1. I Got Stripes Around My Shoulder - Thomas Powledge, the warden who was with us
        Incomplete. Powledge is white; described in the log as a guard.
      - 2. Don't You Hear My Hammer Ring
        Crosscutting
      - 3. Plumb the Line
        Crosscutting; no text here
      - 4. Timber Fallin' Down (Timber gettin' limber) - Chinaman
      - 5. Rattler
        Flatweeding
    - 398 / Rivers Songs / Flatweeding / Chinaman, Mack Maze, Smith, Alec / Ellis / 1230 / 203-9, August 21, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0403; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 5 in.
      Chinaman, Maze, Smith, Alec. Noted on the tape box back: the name "Alberta" and a note that it was raining. Recorded at Ellis. Collector: Bruce Jackson.
      - 1. Black Gal - Chinaman, lead
      - 2. I Shall Be Moved - Chinaman, lead
      - 3. Alberta - Chinaman, lead
        Naming [?]
    - 399 / 1211 / Toasts and Blues, Chinaman bio / Ellis, August 21, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0888; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, quarter track, stereo; 7 in.
      Alec, Chinaman, etc. Recorded at Ellis.
      - 1. The Voodoo Queen - Alec
      - 2. My Reflection - Alec
      - 3. Pa[?] - Mack
      - 4. Going to Move to Kansas City - Chinaman, vocal; Sam Price, guitar
      - 5. Downhearted Blues - Chinaman, vocal; Sam Price, guitar
      - 6. She's a Cousin of Mine - Chinaman, vocal; Sam Price, guitar
      - 7. If You Love Me Like You Say - Will James, vocal; Sam Price, guitar
      - 8. Chinaman talking on himself; toast
    - 400 / Rivers Songs (cording and flatweeding) / Ramsey 1 / 1231, August 22, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0404; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1/2 track, mono; 5 in.
      Johnny Jackson, Houston Page, Arthur Foster, William Evans. Recorded at Ramsey 1. Collector: Bruce Jackson.
      - 1. Down on the River - Johnny, lead
        Cording
      - 2. Black Gal/Stewball [?] - Johnny, lead
      - 3. John Henry - Johnny, lead
      - 4. Raise 'Em Up High - Johnny, lead
      - 5. Down the Line - Page, lead
    - 401 / Rivers Songs (cording and flatweeding) and shoveling / Ramsey 1 / 1232 / 203-9, August 22, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0405; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1/2 track, mono; 5 in.
      Johnny Jackson, Houston Page, Arthur Foster, William Evans. Recorded at Ramsey 1. Collector: Bruce Jackson. A note on the tape box back seems to suggest this recording was made in the same location as SR0404.
      - 1. Down the Line - Page, lead
      - 2. Rattler - Page, lead
      - 3. Yellow Gal - Jackson, lead, then Page leads
      - 4. Cotton Fields - Evans, lead; Page not singing
        Song learned from [?]
      - 5. Chain Gang - Evans, lead
        Working with spades; from Sam Cooke
      - 6. I'm In the Bottom - Jackson, lead
        Spades; shoveling
    - 402 / Rivers Songs (cording and flatweeding), shoveling, talk on songs / Ramsey 1 / 1233, August 22, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0406; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1/2 track, mono; 5 in.
      - 1. I'm in the Bottom - Jackson, lead
        Shoveling
      - 2. Talk on use of songs, style
        Log has "discussing songs, when made up, etc."
      - 3. Crooked Foot John - Johnny Jackson, lead
        He also calls this "John Henry"
      - 4. Grizzly Bear - Jackson and Page, lead
        Shoveling; log only has Jackson singing lead here
      - 5. Conversation on Jack o' Diamonds
      - 6. Joke - Foster
    - 403 / Preaching / Rivers Songs, preaching, joke / Ramsey 1 / 1234, August 22, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0407; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1/2 track, mono; 5 in.
      Johnny Jackson, Houston Page, Arthur Foster, William Evans. "Boss Calvert is the guard who was with us." Recorded at Ramsey 1. Collector: Bruce Jackson.
      - 1. Joke [?] - Foster
      - 2. Sermon - Page
      - 3. I Need Another Witness - J.J., lead (vocal [?]); then Page, lead
    - 404 / MacDonald / Ramsey 2 / 1235, August 22-23, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0408; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 2 track, mono; 5 in.
      Nicknames and slang. Side 1: August 22, 1965; Side 2: August 23, 1965
    - 405 / MacDonald / Ramsey 2 / 1236, August 23, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0409; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 5 in.
      Contents: organized and professional crime. Side 1 recorded at Ramsey. Side 2 recorded at MacDonald.
    - 406 / Toasts / River songs, toasts / J.D. Smith / Ramsey 2 / 1237, August 23, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0410; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 5 in.
      Recorded in dentist office, Ramsey 2; [?] noise from pipes and pumps. Collector: Bruce Jackson.
      - 1. I Got Too Much Time for the Crime I Done (part 1)
        In the log the title appears as "Too Much Time for the Crime Done"; song with conversation
      - 2. I Got Too Much Time for the Crime I Done (part 2)
        See note for song 1
      - 3. Titanic
        Toast; song about Shine
      - 4. They Can't Do That
        Toast with some verses he forgot the other day
      - 5. Conversation on Smith's background
    - 407 / River songs, talk on them / J.D. Smith / Ramsey 2 / 1238, August 23, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0411; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1/2 track, mono; 5 in.
      Recorded at Ramsey 2. Collector: Bruce Jackson. The number 130196, Smith's prisoner number, appears on the tape box.
      - 1. At the Cross
        "Rearranged" hymn
      - 2. Lost John
        Old way; song with introductory material
      - 3. Drop 'Em Down Together
        Tree-cutting song
      - 4. Talk
      - 5. Drinkin' the Wine
      - 6. Fallin' Down
        Timber song
    - 408 / Toasts / River Songs / Ramsey 1 /1239 / reel 1, November 16, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0412; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1/2 track, mono; 5 in.
      Bill McDonald. The tape box back indicates Ramsey 2, and a side panel indicates Ramsey 1.
    - 409 / McDonald / Ramsey 1 / 1240 / reel 2, November 16, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0413; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 5 in.
      Bill McDonald. See note for SR0412.
    - 410 / Prison Stories / Ramsey 1 / 1241 / reel 3, November 16, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0414; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 2 track, mono; 5 in.
      - Frank Sears
      - Jim Miller
      - Roland Tyler
    - 411 / Clark / McDonald / Ramsey 2 / 1242 / reel 4, November 17, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0415; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 2 track, mono; 5 in.
      - Nick Clark [Nate Clark?]
      - Mac
    - 412 / Clark / McDonald / Ramsey 2 / 1243 / reel 5, November 17, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0416; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 2 track, mono; 5 in.
      - Nate Clark
      - Mac
    - 413 / Nate Clark / Ramsey 2 / 1244 / reel 6, November 17, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0417; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 2 track, mono; 5 in.
    - 414 / River Songs / Ramsey 2 / 1245 / reel 7, November 17, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0418; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 2 track, mono; 5 in.
      Performed by J.B. Smith. Collector: Bruce Jackson. Recorded at Ramsey 2.
      - Side A
      - 1. I Got Too Much Time for the Crime I Done
        With new verses
      - 2. No More Good Time in the World for Me
      - Side B
      - 1. No More Good Time in the World for Me (song)
      - 2. Partner Help Me Call 'Em (Whoa Man)
      - 3. Ever Since I Been a Man Full Grown
        Continued on SR0419
    - 415 / River Songs / Ramsey 2 / 1246 / reel 8, November 17, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0419; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 2 track, mono; 5 in.
      Performed by J.B. Smith. Recorded at Ramsey 2. Collector: Bruce Jackson.
      - Side A
      - 1. Ever Since I Been a Man Full Grown
        Continued from tape 7 [SR0418]
      - 2. Woman Trouble
        Song followed by long comment and jokes
      - Side B
      - 1. Woman Trouble
        Conclusion of the song
      - 2. Boy holds job
    - 416 / Stories, Toasts / Ramsey 2 / 1247 / reel 9, November 17, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0420; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 2 track, mono; 5 in.
      Performed by J.B. Smith. Recorded at Ramsey 2.
      - Side A
      - John and the [?]
      - John's [?]
      - toasts
    - 417 / Characters / Ramsey 2 / 1248 / reel 10, November 18, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0421; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 5 in.
      Recorded at Ramsey 2.
      - Side A
      - 1. York: bio
      - 2. Bill McDonald
      - Side B
      - 1. II
    - 418 / Songs Crime Talk / Ramsey 2 / 1249 / reel 11, November 18, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0422; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 5 in.
      - Side A: Frank York
      - 1. Tale on songs, style
      - 2. Take This Hammer
      - 3. This Old Tree
      - 4. Talk on songs
      - Side B: Lawrence Turner
    - 419 / Prison, Comp. / Lawrence Turner / Ramsey 2 / 1250 / reel 12, November 17-18, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0423; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, 2 track, mono; 5 in.
      Contents: Texas, Leavenworth, Colorado: comparisons. Recorded at Ramsey 2. The tape box back indicates the tape was recorded on November 17; the side panel indicates November 18.
    - 420 / Blues / River Songs / Ramsey 2 / 1251 / reel 13, November 18, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0424; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 2 track, mono; 5 in.
      Recorded at Ramsey 2. Collector: Bruce Jackson.
      - Side A
      - 1. Turn Row Blues (from Hopkins record) - Frank York, vocal and piano
        Learned from Hopkins record
      - 2. Honey - Frank York, vocal and piano
        Cotton-pickin' song
      - 3. Sure Makes a Man Feel Bad - Smith, lead; Houston, Zachary, York
      - 4. Old Aunt Dinah - G.I. and group
      - Side B
      - 1. Talk on Maze [?]
        The log has "conversation about Tom Moore"
      - 2. Long Gone [?] Lot John
        Minstrel song
      - 3. I'm So Glad My Time Have Come - J.B. Smith
    - 421 / Jokes, Nicknames / Ramsey 1 and 2 / 1252 / reel 14, November 18, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0425; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 2 track, mono; 5 in.
      Recorded at Ramsey 1 and 2.
      - Side A
      - 1. [?] - G.I. and Zachary
      - 2. Big George and Little George - G.I. and Zachary
      - 3. Little Nigger and Big Nigger - G.I. and Zachary
      - 4. Drop That Log - G.I. and Zachary
      - [no number] More of those here
      - [no number] Nicknames [?] - Roland Tyler
    - 422 / Jokes / Addiction / Ramsey 1 / 1253 / reel 15, November 18, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0426; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 5 in.
      Recorded at Ramsey 1.
      - 1. Joke - Roland Tyler
      - 2. On narco [?] - Jim
    - 423 / Alexander / Ellis / 1254, January 6, 1966, AFC 2011/009: SR0427; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 2 track, mono; 5 in.
      Recorded at Ellis.
      - 1. Two dub from T[?] B[?]
      - 2. Nicknames - Alec
    - 424 / River Songs / Phillips, Mitchell, Tippen / Wynne / 1255, January 6, 1966, AFC 2011/009: SR0428; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 5 in.
      Recorded at Wynne.
      - 1. I'm Gonna Write My Mama and Tell Her Pray for Me (Phillips P.) - Tippen and others, lead
        Copies "Don't You Never Feel Sorry"
      - 2. Godamighty - Tippen
      - 3. Grizzly Bear - Tippen [?]
      - [unnumbered] Conversation about Jack o Diamonds
        Listed on the log but not the tape box
      - 4. Hammer Ring - Tippen, lead
      - 5. Midnight Special - Tippen, lead
        Song, followed by talk
      - 6. [unidentified] - [?], lead singer
        Listed on the tape box but not the log